Contact

bhoxmark@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/bhoxmark (LinkedIn) github.com/hoxmark (Other)

Top Skills

Software Development
Data Cleaning
Data Science

Languages

Bokmål, Norwegian (Native or Bilingual)

English (Full Professional)

Bjørn Hoxmark

Data Scientist

Oslo, Oslo, Norway

Summary

I'm a curious Data Scientist currently working with machine learning and recommender systems at FINN.no. I'm working on finding ways to leverage NLP in our job matching engine on our job market place. Previously I have worked as a software developer and have a MSc from NTNU. Computers and Technology has always been an interest of mine and I love learning new things.

Experience

FINN.no – mulighetenes marked Data Scientist September 2018 - Present (5 years 5 months) Oslo, Oslo, Norway

Working with recommender systems at Finn.no, with a focus towards the job vertical.

FINN.no – mulighetenes marked Software Engineer June 2017 - August 2017 (3 months) Oslo Area, Norway

During the summer I worked in a team on two different projects:

- 1. We redesigned and rewrote the admin page for an ad on Finn using NodeJS and React.
- 2. Implemented a new feature on the ad-page for customers to give feedback directly to the seller. Here we used Spring Boot. For more information please read the attached blogpost.

Nordic Semiconductor ASA 7 months

Software Engineer August 2016 - December 2016 (5 months)

Software Engineer
June 2016 - July 2016 (2 months)

Developed and released a tool for developers who work with low energy bluetooth mesh-enabled projects.

The tool was created as a desktop application for Windows, OSX and Linux, written in HTML, CSS, JS with JavaScript libraries such as React, Redux and Electron.

To read more about the tool please see the blog post:

Norsk energiteknikk 3 years 8 months

Technical Support Agent June 2012 - August 2015 (3 years 3 months) Asker

Supporting Shell Norways GSSP system, Bunker Oil's system and independent gasoline sites. (Mainly during the summers)

Technical Support Agent January 2012 - August 2012 (8 months) Asker, Norway

Supported the new GSSP system that Shell Norway use. Learned a lot about how a new product is introduced, with support and pilot sites and finding temporary work arounds.

Fujitsu
Technical Support Agent
July 2011 - January 2012 (7 months)
Supported the new GSSP system that Shell Norway use.

Education

Norwegian University of Science and Technology (NTNU) Master of Science - MS, Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence · (2016 - 2018)

University of California, Santa Barbara

Master of Science (MSc), Computer Science · (2017 - 2017)

Norwegian University of Science and Technology (NTNU) Engineer's Degree, Computer Software Engineering (2013 - 2016)